(null)
BRAD GREEN: Welcome.
Hey, I'm Brad Green.
I run the Angular
project at Google.
I'm excited you
guys could join us.
We're all pretty excited
on the Angular team.
And we're not good at
ceremony, so we're just
kind of announcing, we're
calling Angular2 in alpha,
meaning there are some
bits out there on GitHub,
and we'll show you later
how to get to them.
But there are some bits
that you can go play with.
And tonight David East
of the Firebase team
is going to come and show us
the fantastic TodoMVC app done
in Angular2.
The presentation is maybe
only about 20 minutes.
We will be up here,
Misko, and Igor,
and Naomi and some
other folks in the team
will be taking questions that
you might have about Angular2.
And we'll skirt issues when
you asked about the timeline,
but you can ask us real
questions about Angular2.
And we can really answer
them because things
are fairly real now.
So as always when
you ask questions
we're going to have
you sign a form that
says it's OK to release
them to YouTube.
So please only
ask stuff that you
want to have on live stream.
We're excited to
be here tonight.
I'll have David come
up and we'll get going.
David, where'd you go?
Oh, there you are.
OK.
Thanks.
(null)
DAVID EAST: How's
everyone doing?
Is this good?
All right.
This kind of gets
away from me at times.
And then I'll talk over
here and you can't hear me.
Just keep me in check.
All right.
So I'm really excited to talk
to you guys here tonight.
I think we have a little
bit of an interesting topic
that you might
want to hear about.
So we're going to be
talking about Angular2.
So for those of you
who don't know me,
my name is [INAUDIBLE].
I am a developer program
engineer at Google
where I work on Firebase.
I actually only work
on Angular part time
where I work on the
developer experience, which
is essentially like creating
great documentation, code
samples, and all the things
that are going to make all
of your lives
hopefully a lot easier.
So this time around if you have
any problems of documentation
you know who to throw things at.
So I've actually only
been working on a Angular2
for about a month now.
So I kind of find it
kind of surreal and crazy
that within a month time
frame of saying, sure,
I can help [INAUDIBLE].
Here I am talking to
you all about something
that's in an alpha stage.
So for the past month I've
just been bugging the core team
with all these
questions while they've
been coding away like crazy.
And just sort of every day I
get a fresh new copy of Angular2
and make new stuff with it.
So this presentation
is sort of what
I've been able to
pull away from that.
So like always in something
in alpha this is a disclaimer.
It's kind of like what you
see at the bottom of the email
when someone says, don't talk
about this if you received
it or something.
Angular2 is a work in progress.
Things might slash will
probably, definitely
will change.
So everything you see in here,
don't hold me accountable
if you see this later and
you built an app on this.
I'm sorry.
All right.
Before we get talking about a
lot of the concepts of Angular2
I want to talk about
the motivation.
Why are we building Angular2?
What are the things
that are different?
And what we're
looking to address?
And then once that's
done, we're going
to talk about concepts, like
all the new stuff in Angular2
that's really cool, the
building blocks, and all that.
And like Brad said it's only
about 20 minutes so there's not
enough time for me
to cover everything.
There is a lot more than what's
on here, but if I went more
it would be just
total mind blown,
like how do I learn
all these things.
So we're just going to
focus on the very basics.
And after that I'm going
to show the Todo app
I created, which is
also very simple.
And that's up on GitHub,
so you guys will be able
check it out afterwards, too.
All right.
So motivation behind Angular 1.
Well, it's an aging framework.
It dates back all
the way to 2009.
So a lot of things in
2009 didn't really exist.
Right now we are looking
into the Shadow DOM, and ES6
modules, and ES6 in general, and
that wasn't really around then.
So Angular kind of
created its own things
that helped out there.
So now with Angular2 we don't
need things like transclusion
anymore, because that's
what the Shadow DOM does.
It provides that
for us natively.
And then also with ES6 modules,
they replace Angular Modules.
Angular wants to be able to
sit on top of web standards.
It's not the point of
creating a web standard,
or creating a
standard of your own,
and then using that, we want to
play nice as the web evolves.
(null)
Another thing is performance.
So speed is obviously
very important.
And I have a quote
from Misko, which was,
I'm quoting him from
tomorrow, and it's he said,
"today Angular2 is 5x
faster than Angular 1."
So after that hopefully
it will be faster,
but tomorrow it is
five times faster.
And if you don't believe me
I have a chart to prove it,
because charts mean
it's legitimate.
So to the very right over here,
or I guess my left, your right,
we have Angular 1.
And so this is a
deep tree benchmark,
which I should mention.
So this essentially represents
a very complex Angular
application, very
deep rooted, nested
components, which we'll talk
about what components are,
but just think about
very heavily nested DOM,
which essentially makes
up an application.
So that's all the way
out here to the left.
And this is with Angular 1.
And this is how fast
Angular 1 is with that.
And then this is the baseline.
And this is a fixed cost.
So this is essentially
its hard coded way
of building this
type of application.
So it's going to be really
fast because everything's hard
coded.
You would never do
this in real life,
but this is how we
can say, OK, this
is as fast-- this is a
bottom level of speed.
And then this over
here is Angular2
with two different
types of optimizations,
or, I guess, with
one optimization
and one not optimized.
So Angular2, obviously lower
in this case is better.
And Angular2, without a view
cache, which is essentially
without a way of being smart
about how we're managing
our views, is three times
slower than the baseline.
And the Angular2
with the view cache,
which is being smart about
keeping around our elements
is only 1.4 times slower
than the baseline.
And as you can see this
is very, very close.
And this is just today or
tomorrow as Misko told me.
(null)
Another thing is the
simple cognitive model.
So when you're first
learning Angular,
it has a lot of concepts.
And each one of these concepts
has its own learning curve.
You could spend an
entire day learning
about all of the different
things of a controller.
And you could start
learning about all
of the different
things that you can
use transclusion
and directives for.
So this is just a list
of all the concepts
that we first start
learning out in Angular 1.
And what's kind of
funny about the slide,
too, is there's actually more
and the screen clipped the rest
off.
So we kind of start out
learning these things
and these are all
great concepts.
And once we learn
them, you kind of
feel like an advanced
Angular user.
And you can know well how
to use your controller.
You know the difference between
factory service provider
and you're able to have
all this flexibility.
Well, with Angular we want
to provide this flexibility.
With Angular2 we want to provide
this flexibility for you guys,
but maybe do away with a lot
of these conceptual models
and still have the same power
and flexibility as before.
So later I'm going to
show you how we take away
some of these concepts.
Now the motivation
is web standards.
We want to sit on top of web
standards, not create our own.
And performance, so
being as fast as possible
while still introducing
less concepts for you
guys to learn about.
So a lot of you
have seen Angular2,
but for those who haven't
this is sort of your not
so first, maybe kind of
first look at Angular2.
And I'll just let it
sink in for a second.
You guys kind of
take a look at it.
All right.
Now before we say what
this actually does,
let's talk about the syntax
because that's important.
What's happening?
Some of you might be
looking at this saying,
is the Dart version?
Is this Java?
Is this GWT back?
I'm not really sure
what's happening.
So trust me, GWT is not back.
This is AtScript.
And AtScript is
really not too much.
It provides syntactical sugar
for metadata annotations,
which is this @ sign right
here, that @ component,
that's AtScript.
If you wondered what
AtScript stands for,
it's literally just @
script, AtScript, so nothing
too special.
So something to
know about AtScript
is it's not here to
replace JavaScript.
It's not the intention.
It's merely syntactical
sugar on top of ES6.
It also does types,
but we're not even
going to talk about
types because it's not
required with AtScript.
Another cool thing
about AtScript
is the Angular team is
working with TypeScript, V8,
and a bunch of other people
to get this actually worked
into a proposal for
the TC39 committee.
So putting this towards
the future of JavaScript.
(null)
Another thing about
AtScript is you may say,
that's cool and
all, but I really
don't want to write
any of this new stuff.
Well, AtScript compiles
to ES5, so you can still
write all the JavaScript
code that you know today.
It's not required at all.
And like I said, types are
completely optional as well.
All right.
So back to the component.
So we're going to focus on
what this actually does now.
And now that we know the
TypeScript's not scary,
syntactical sugar on top of ES6.
So this whole thing
is called a component.
And a component is
how we structure
and reason about our UI.
An entire Angular application
is just a tree of components.
And as you can see we
have the first part
of the component, which is
the metadata annotation @
component.
And this describes
what our component is.
So we have the selector,
which is the actual HTML
tag that will be this component.
And then we have
the template, which
excuse the template config,
this is some of the stuff
that you'll see changing.
And then within
there is the URL,
so where my template
actually lives.
So within this
Component annotation
I can say simply, all
right, this is the selector,
this is where my template lives.
There's a lot more
that can be done here,
but this is pretty
much the bare minimum
you can get going for
creating a component.
And the second
part is the class.
Now a class, this
is not AtScript.
This is ES6.
And within the class we call
this the Component controller.
So we have a component and you
have a Component controller,
or a Component annotation
and a Component controller.
Component annotation,
like I said,
tells you everything about how
your component gets wired up.
The controller is what
your template reads from.
So how we used to attach things
to scope or use controller
as syntax, we don't have to
attach any of these things
anymore.
It just automatically happens.
The templates are self reading
from this Component controller.
So within a template
I can say todos
and I know that it's
my components todos.
And it's the two items.
So I could say todos that
length and I could bind to that.
So one more time
and all together.
We have Component annotation and
we have a Component controller.
And together this
makes one component.
Those are the two parts.
(null)
So now we understand briefly
how we create components.
It's two simple steps.
But we need to understand how
do we get this on the page
because that's the end goal
of all of what development is,
get something to
appear on the page.
So the current bootstrapping
process in Angular 1.
We have Angular dot module
and we specifier our app name.
Then we have to wire up
ng-app and specify that also
with the app name.
And then we create a controller,
attach things to $scope.
And then we have to
say the ng-controller.
And you can do
ng-view, but this is
just one of the simpler
ways of getting it set up.
And specify the template.
And this is roughly six steps.
Like we said, Create
Module, ng-app,
create controller, attach items
to $scope, Declare Controller,
Create Template.
And each one of these things is
probably only one to two lines
of code each, but they're
very dependent on each other.
If you misspell the
app name, it blows up.
If you get forget
ng-app, you kind of
refresh the page over and
over again asking yourself,
why is this happening.
And then you realize you
forgot the directive.
In Angular2 this is
a lot more simple.
This essentially is your
bootstrapping process.
We already know how
we create component.
So @Component, and then we can
say export class component,
which essentially means
give this out to the world.
This is ES6 syntax as well.
And then down here we have more
ES6 syntax where we bootstrap.
So we import Bootstrap
from angular,
because Bootstrap is a
function provided by Angular,
so it's a manual
bootstrapping process.
And then we import the Todo app
that we exported out from here.
And then we say,
Bootstrap, this Todo app.
And that essentially
is your process.
The only other thing that I
have sneakily not included
is the template.
So you'll need a template, which
is URL slash Todo slash html,
but we're going to get into
template syntax in just
a second.
So there is one little piece
that I didn't mention though
and that is the ES6 to
AtScript compilation.
If you're using ES6
or AtScript, that's
going to run in any
modern browser right now.
So you'll have to use your
favorite ES6 compiler.
Traceur works very
well with AtScript.
It has experimental options
that allow you to specify that.
And it actually
works in the browser,
which the TodoMVC
app uses no CLI.
It all works in browser.
And right now you
have to use systemjs
to import these modules as
sort of a module loading shim,
but right now we're working
on sort of a key turn solution
where you don't have to worry
about the crazy ES6 module
loading world.
So we saw the six steps
before, but now it's just four.
And hopefully number
four goes away one day
because it's just
the bridge to writing
the code we want to
write for tomorrow.
So we create a component,
give it a template, bootstrap.
And sadly, transpile
until that goes away.
And if you write ES5 code you
don't have to transpile at all.
So it's a much more
simple model for getting
started with your Angular app.
All right.
So we've talked about
creating a component and how
we get it to appear on a page.
But now we have new
templates syntax.
Now, I threw a lot of
new code at you again.
So I'm going to give you all
a second to let this sink in.
Where we were creating
the component,
the code block below
is its templates.
(null)
All right.
So now that I think you guys
have looked at it a little bit,
we have this
template right here.
And essentially this component
is called name-change.
All it does is just
changes a name.
We type into a text box,
we click Enter, and then
that updates.
And as you can see right
here we have the div
that displays the name, the
text box, and the button.
You recognize the curlies,
but what you probably
don't recognize is the
pound sign, the brackets,
and the parentheses.
So I'm going to go through
each one of these one by one.
So sort of a new concept in
Angular2 is Local Variables.
And this is something that
I was kind of geeking out
when I first starting using it.
I was like, oh my gosh.
I can't believe this
actually exists.
And what you can do
here is by you saying,
pound sign on this text
box, it gives me a handle.
So it's now Local Variable
to just the template.
It doesn't bleed out into
the $scope anywhere else.
It just lives inside
your template.
And I can actually
bind it to the page.
So I say, newname.value
and that's
the property of that input.
So if I change the value,
it changes on the page.
And where this comes in
handy is with Event Handlers.
And that's where we
saw the parentheses.
So you see parentheses click.
And we say click
equals changeName
and that is a function on
my Component controller.
And from there I can pass in
the event that was clicked on.
And then I also can say
newname.value and that
passes that back into my
Component controller method.
So in just two lines of HTML
I've created a Local Variable
and I've passed its value.
It's very declarative.
I don't have to say
[INAUDIBLE], getElementById.
I don't have to do
anything to find it.
It's very easy to look
at this and reason
that I am grabbing the
value when I click a button.
And lastly with the
array bracket syntax
is Property Bindings.
Now we're used to binding
to attributes in Angular 1.
But in Angular2, this
is a bit different.
Rather than binding
to attributes
we're binding to actual
properties of a DOM element.
So if you were to write
document.getElementByID
for a span you could say
whatever the span handle
is dot text content, and that
will tell you whatever the text
[INAUDIBLE] time.
There's no such thing as
a text content attribute.
So from here I'm binding to
properties, not attributes.
So now when I update
this text box,
I can say whenever the
newname.value changes
I'm going to update it to
the text content of the span.
(null)
So we'll look at
this one more time
and so we can reason
about what's going on.
We know that we're displaying
the name from the Component
controller because we
have our name property.
And then down here
we have a text box,
which we gave the Local
Variable of newname.
When this button
is clicked, which
we know because of
the parentheses,
we call the function
changeName, which
is inside of our
Component controller.
And we pass that
the newname.value,
which our changeName does.
It expects a new name.
And then we just simply say
this dot name equals new name
and our name gets updated.
(null)
And one of the
really great benefits
of using this new
syntax is uniformity.
Whenever I'm declaring
an Event Handler
I know I just need to
use the parentheses.
And any type of event
can fit in there.
So if we want to do a
mouseover, a double-click,
I can use this
front end developer
knowledge I know about,
all these DOM events,
and I just need to know
the syntax for Angular2.
I don't have to worry about
knowing about the ng click
directive, or the ng
model, or ng double-click.
There's no one-to-one directive
to event ratio anymore.
This works for all
events, including
custom events on Web Components.
And then we also
know that whenever
we want to bind to a property we
just use array bracket syntax.
So [INAUDIBLE] I
was saying, there
was always the difference
between ng model, ng click.
You had to really know what
that directive did to use it.
And then now I know
what a property is.
I know this syntax.
I know I'm binding to
that syntax right away.
There's no just diving
into the documentation,
seeing what are the
side effects of this.
Just by knowing the syntax,
it's easy to reason about.
But what this also does,
it provides us flexibility.
So when we create Web Components
one of the great new things
about that is you can
create custom events.
So I could create a Web
Component that fires out a name
change event, but
the problem with that
is that I now have to create
an ng-name-change event.
And that's what this
top thing is doing.
It's from Angular 1.
So now I've got to say
ng-name-change and write
the directive for that.
But in Angular2 I
won't have to do that.
I know I have a brand
new name change event.
So I just pass it
into the parentheses.
I don't create a directive.
I don't do anything at all.
It's completely supported.
(null)
So we know how to
create components.
We can bootstrap them up.
And we see the new
template syntax.
But what happens
when things change?
How does that actually happen?
Well, the great news is that
you don't really have to care.
It kind of works magically.
But if you want to know
what's under the hood,
and I apologize for this.
This doesn't come out too
well in the resolution.
But this is how Angular2
change detection works.
And this is, in my opinion,
one of the coolest things
that I've seen while
working with it.
So an Angular2 application
is just a tree of components.
And this component,
and by the way,
this is taken from Angular core
teamer Vic Savkin's blog post,
which is really awesome.
So I recommend doing the
read for more information.
But in this case we have an
app component at the top.
And then an app
component has a child,
which is a Todos component,
which has a child of a Todo.
Now whenever a change
happens it goes down one way.
And it starts at
the app component,
and it runs change
detection, and then
it can go down to each one
of the child components.
And change detection
is really smart.
So it works at a module level.
So each component only has to
update its individual updates.
And also, if we do more
advanced things, such as using
immutable data or observables,
this component tree
can be very smart
and say, well I'm
not going to update this
because I know it's immutable.
So it gives you
faster performance.
But you could do a
really big talk on this.
And I know that Vic will be.
So there will be more
information about this later.
So the change detection runs,
but how does change detection
know to run?
And this is one of
the new libraries
used in Angular called Zone.
And so Zone is kind of like
the Professor X of Angular,
Professor X of JavaScript.
Whenever an asynchronous
event happens
it just lets Angular know,
hey, something has happened.
Run change detection.
And then so change detection
runs and everything
gets updated.
And a good example of this,
for those of you who have ever
dealt with asynchronous
events in Angular
is when you have to use
$timeout, so dollar timeout.
In this case this is
some Firebase code.
And what I'm doing is I'm
attaching a callback function
whenever something
updates in Firebase.
And Angular does not know
anything about Firebase.
So if I want this to be updated
in my view I call $timeout
and I said, scope that user
to snap that [? valve. ?]
So this is what we
currently do in Angular 1.
And this isn't terribly a
performant way of doing it
or an easy way to do it.
I pretty much spend
most of my days
answering Stack Overflow
questions about this.
So what's great
about Angular2 is
that we don't have
to do this anymore.
Change detection in
Angular2 is much smarter.
Whenever this callback
function fires off
Zone says, hey, by the way, this
callback function fired off.
Angular says, thanks for
letting me know about it.
I'm going to run
change detection.
And then everything
just sort of happens.
So now when we're
writing our code that
lives outside of
Angular we don't
have to know about digest,
apply, timeouts, or anything
like that.
That just happens.
And we can go about
writing the code,
writing JavaScript
that we know how
to write without worrying
about how Angular works.
All right.
So that is pretty much the
core basic concepts of Angular.
So we'll take a
look at the code.
All right.
Well, first I'm going to
show you how it works.
So this is an Angular2 Todo app.
And like I said, this is
pretty washed out on this one,
but what I can do is I can
say, OK, what do I need to do?
I need to give a talk.
And this is written in Firebase.
So if I refresh the
page, give a talk.
So it persists.
So I can do things
like check off a list,
and then I can say,
OK, clear completed.
And that works.
So it all works.
And when I wrote the
Firebase piece of this,
I didn't write a
single $timeout,
a single anything like that.
It was just all regular code.
And when we actually need to
port the AngularFire library
over, it'll actually
involve a lot less code
than what we need to do to
get it to work in Angular 1.
So this is the source code.
And essentially each part--
this Todo app is three parts.
We have this header,
where the text box lives.
We have the main, which is
where we render our Todos.
And then we have this
footer, which gives us
all of these action
items down here.
So we're going to
do a little bit
of switching back and forth.
So it's easy for you guys
to see what's going on.
So we'll open up the header.
And the way this header works
is is the ID of new-todo
is just for styling.
And then placeholder and
autofocus, just regular
attributes.
And with newtodo I've given
it the local variable.
I say on keyup call my
Component Controller method,
enterTodo with the
event given and newtodo.
So now I'm going to go into
my Component controller.
(null)
And right here we have-- where
would I have entered todo.
(null)
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
DAVID EAST: Thank you.
See?
I need you guys.
All right.
So what I do in here
is I get that event.
I can say, hey, which
key was pressed?
If so, call this.addTodo,
which is another method.
And then I pass in
the newTodo.value,
clear out the Todo.
And if we see addTodo
all addTodo is calls
this.todoService, which is
my AngularFire service .add
and sends that data
out to Firebase.
So that's pretty simple.
So we'll go and look
at the body now.
So look at the main piece.
And we have right here,
we have the ability
to say click toggleAll.
So when I say toggleAll
I check to see
if the checkbox is checked.
If it's not, toggle all
of them, untoggle them.
And then inside here we
have a new little piece
that I didn't have
any slides on,
but it's definitely
worth talking about.
We have this bang forEach.
And this is the replacement
syntax for ng repeat.
So now we can say bang
forEach, local Variable Todo,
in the list of Todos.
Inside of here is what will be
repeated, so each list item.
And then from in here
you can see actually
where we're binding to class.
We can get even more
specific to that.
Rather than just
binding to a class
we can bind to a specific class.
So class.hidden is equal
if the current Todo that's
being rendered is the Todo
that's also being edited.
And just like as you
see in the slides
we can bind to the click,
or binding to check.
And then we're also
binding to double-click.
So this all is very
uniform syntax.
(null)
And then down here I
actually completed this code.
I didn't actually
want this to be done.
So we'll pretend like
that's not there.
And now that that
was never there,
if we wanted to add a
click event to clear
all of the completed
ones, we say, click.
(null)
We say that it's
clear completed.
Now we go into our Todo
Component controller.
This method down here at the
bottom is clear completed.
It just gathers
all the Todos that
have been marked as completed.
And then it sends it
off to the Todo servers
to clear all of them.
And so from there when I check
things off, clear completed,
it works.
So it's very simple
to reason about
what's an event, what's
being clicked on,
and how I can actually
get the values to pass
into these events.
All right.
(null)
So that's what we
have for you today.
We are going to be able to
answer a lot more questions
because I'm sure you have a few.
There is no documentation yet.
And so you can throw that at me.
I just said, I'm responsible
for documentation.
I tell you there's
no documentation.
I actually have
something planned
that'll be out probably
within a week or two
that will be pretty cool.
And it'll cover pretty
much this information
in an interactive
tutorial format.
If you want to check
out the code for this
that will be posted.
There's a GitHub repo for that.
And ng-conf is going to be
very much Angular2 centric.
So all of these advanced
things, all of the stuff
that I wasn't even able to
talk to you about today,
like routing and
dependency injection,
that stuff's going to be
talked a lot more at ng-conf.
So there's a lot more
to be excited about.
And we'll be at [? NPM ?] soon.
So that'll be cool, too.
So all right.
That's what I got.
If you've got any questions.
[APPLAUSE]
(null)
BRAD GREEN: David, why don't
you just stay up there.
Misko, can you come up?
And I will run the
microphone around.
And yeah, why don't
you come up too, Naomi,
if you would please?
(null)
Questions.
Everybody's flabbergasted
at the new syntax.
I understand.
(null)
Yes?
Question here.
AUDIENCE: What are the
functional differences
between Local
Variables and ng model?
So is a Local Variable available
from the actual business logic?
(null)
MISKO: So the
question is what is
the difference between a
Local Variable and ng model.
So unfortunately what
this demo did not show
is there's going to
be support for forms.
And so David
cheated a little bit
by simply binding to events,
and getting the data out
of the input elements that way.
So the forms are the
replacement for ng model.
And at the end of
the day, really it
should be as simple as changing
the syntax from ng model
to something else.
It's going to be some
semantic changes.
But fundamentally it's going
to work very similarly.
You're not going to see it.
The reason for the
change is because we
want to make sure
that we can retain
this directed acyclic graph.
And we have to make sure that
any reverse bindings, in order
to get the full
circle going, has
to execute before
the change detection.
And so this is
kind of the reason
we have to move things around,
but at the end of the day
what you're going to get
is going to very much feel
like two-way data binding,
even though under the hood
we're going to have to do
some tricks to make it happen
in the proper order so
it's very predictable.
(null)
Right.
So two-way data binding.
That's kind of a love
hate relationship.
IGOR: [INAUDIBLE]
MISKO: So there is
this thing in Angular 1
[INAUDIBLE] if you
have two components
and they're bound
to each other, you
can actually set the
directionality of it
to be two-way data-binding.
And that actually seems
like a good idea at first
until you have a large
scale application.
And then it turns out that you
have no idea what's going on,
who's binding to what,
who's updating what.
And it turns out to be kind of
an anti-pattern for large apps.
So to make the large
apps more predictable,
and easier to
understand, and debug,
and so on we opted for this
idea of directed acyclic graph,
which means that you cannot
have any pointers going
in the reverse direction.
And it turns out all
kinds of wonderful things
happen if you do that.
But it makes certain
things not possible,
which is mainly
two-way data-binding.
And so what we do,
again, we go back
to this form which says
that we want to give you
a syntax that's going to look
like two-way data-binding,
but actually it's going to
be a very clear state when
a reverse direction happens and
a forward direction happens.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: Over there.
I'll go back here and then
I'll come up front here.
(null)
AUDIENCE: What about cross
controller communication,
like in [INAUDIBLE] broadcast
and stuff like that?
I mean, they're not great but
sometimes they're [INAUDIBLE].
MISKO: So how do you do cross
controller communication?
That's a good question.
We're also changing
that one a little bit.
So it turns out there's actually
two different kinds of events
you can do in two
components communicating.
The two components that don't
actually know about each other.
So, for example, person
A implements a fancy text
in a calendar widget.
And person B wants
to go and consume it.
In this case because they
don't know about each other,
kind of the DOM event model kind
of broadcasting and emitting
is kind of the way
you want to do this.
But we do that on a DOM level,
so that the component emitting
it says, I'm emitting
event foo And then you
do parentheses foo in
order to listen to it.
The other mode of
communication is
that within a single
application when
you have two components that
have very tight coupling.
So, for example, you have
a tic-tack-toe application
and it has components that
is an individual cell.
In that case the better way to
do it instead of doing events--
you can certainly do
events-- but a better way
to do it is to simply inject
the app into the child,
and simply call methods on it.
And the benefits of that
is that while it gives you
a tight coupling, presumably
the two components
are already tightly
coupled because they're
part of the same app,
and you can do things
like navigating
inside of the IDs.
So you just have
a function call.
And you can click
through the function call
and get to the destination.
So we give you these
two different modes
that you can do.
And hopefully that
solves your problem.
BRAD GREEN: Up front here.
AUDIENCE: So going back
to your previous comment
you were making, so the example
David showed, if I recall,
he basically had the events
and he passed a Local Variable
that went to the function.
And presumably
the value changed.
Doesn't it kind of conflict
with what you were stating?
Because then you
have no idea what's
changing the value to
the local parameter.
MISKO: So there's the kind
of digest phase, which
updates the data binding.
But there's also what I
don't have a good name for,
but I just call it
the reverse binding,
which is what gets
the data from the UI
and kind of gets it to the
application, which then you
can do data binding on.
So what you see
in the parentheses
is really the reverse
mode data binding.
What you see inside of brackets
is the forward data binding.
That's kind of the distinction.
There's a couple other
distinctions in there,
but those are fundamentally
what's going on.
BRAD GREEN: Back
in the back there.
I'm coming around.
Don't move.
(null)
AUDIENCE: What about
$scope inheritance?
Is it going to be
like class inheritance
because I see here often
when we refer to a template,
there's a possibility
that the template in turn
refers to another widget,
I mean, [INAUDIBLE]
into a sub-directive.
And how was data going to
flow through that chain?
MISKO: Is this about
$scoping inheritance
or referring to directives?
AUDIENCE: $scoping
inheritance, but I
can see even the
sub-directives, they
most likely share
inherit from the parent.
MISKO: Yeah.
I think I understand
your question.
So I think what you're asking
is that in Angular 1x, $scopes
inherited it from each other.
And so if you have
a component, you
would automatically
get the parents.
So in Anugular2, because
of the components,
you can think of Angular2
component as a Angular 1x
$scope that has private state.
What is it called?
IGOR: Isolate scope.
MISKO: Isolate $scope.
AUDIENCE: OK.
So we can choose to pass
whatever information
from the parent's $scope.
MISKO: Yeah.
So you use data binding.
So there's two modes you can do.
Actually, there's three.
You can data bind it through
the bracket notation.
You can dependency inject
it and you can dependency
inject the parent controller
into the child controller,
which is something that
was not shown here.
And you can actually
do the reverse thing
where you could actually
query your children.
So there's kind of
three modes of which you
can get a hold of these things.
And they actually play
to different strengths
and weaknesses.
Depending on the
situation you are
in you might want to
use one or the other.
And by giving you
these choices this
actually becomes a
lot more expressive
in what you're trying to do.
AUDIENCE: But then
when you have templates
and you said that the
$scope of a variable
is within that template, say,
for example, when we declared
a new name and the
newname.value was
available throughout
the template.
So it seems like to
me when a template
is embedded inside
another template,
so everyone gets to share
all the values, right?
MISKO: So what's
different in Angular2
is that we're built on
top of Web Components.
And Web Components have this
thing called a shadow DOM.
And even if your browser
doesn't have shadow DOM
we're going to
pretend as if it did,
and we're going to
kind of emulate it.
So the new terminology,
rather than
inventing our own
terminology of transclusion,
and isolated $scopes, and who
gets what, we're simply saying,
look, there is already
a terminology out there.
It's called Web Components.
And we just follow that.
Now what the Web
Components gives you is it
gives you isolations.
Good programming principles
says if you have a function,
it should be isolated from
another function, right?
And because of these isolations
the variables actually
don't flow very far.
They only stay within a
particular component's view.
And they're not visible
inside of child views,
or parent views.
So there's actually pretty
strong isolation guarantees
in there.
It's actually a good
thing because it
allows you to build
large apps and you
don't have worry
that you accidentally
clobber each other,
that they have
the same name, or the
importing of things.
It's really properly
isolated this time.
AUDIENCE: Thanks.
BRAD GREEN: Cool.
Next question.
(null)
Yes, back row.
I'm getting over there.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Will the
templates end up
taking advantage of some of the
web components in shadow DOM
stuff for styling, so
encapsulated CSS instead
of having to do
ID everywhere to--
(null)
MISKO: The short answer is yes.
We'll take advantage of this.
So Web Components,
rather, shadow DOM
is available in Chrome and--
IGOR: Chrome.
MISKO: Chrome and Chrome.
OK.
[LAUGHTER]
Now it will be sad if
Angular only ran on Chrome.
So what we do is
we say, OK, well,
we think the future is shadow
DOM and Web Components.
And therefore, we're going
just take the vocabulary
that Web Components provides.
So you're going to have
to learn about shadow
DOM, the light DOM, the
[? group ?] projection, and all
this stuff that Web
Components provide.
The nice thing is,
any framework that's
going to be on top
of web components
will have the same
exact vocabulary.
And what we're
going to do then is
we're going to actually run the
Angular in one of, I believe,
four modes.
You can either use shadow
DOM where it's required.
And so obviously would
only run on Chrome.
Or we're going to enter
emulated mode, where we're
going to pretend
we have shadow DOM.
So we're going to have
the same semantics,
but obviously there
is no shadow DOM.
Now in that mode we can actually
subdivide in two different sub
modes when it comes to styling.
We can either properly
isolate the CSS styles
by reading the CSS and
then prefixing everything
with a component name.
And then writing it back out.
And so that's going
to give you isolation.
But for people who have never
done Web Components or shadow
roots, it's going to
be like, surprise.
Why does it work this way?
Why is the styling [INAUDIBLE]?
So we actually have a different
mode, which doesn't do this.
So by default we're going to
pretend we have Web Components,
but we're not
going to do styling
unless you actually opt into it.
Then there's going to be a
couple of learnings to do.
These are actually
not our learnings.
This is just the standard
of Web Components, right?
So if you opt into
this and you're
willing to do all this
extra work that the Web
Components will kind of
require of you in order
to get proper isolation,
we're going to support it.
So that's going to be nice.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: Cool.
More questions?
Oh, in front here.
(null)
AUDIENCE: So my question
is, in Angular 1
we use services a lot.
So service kind
of a [INAUDIBLE],
which is a way to share the
data in different components.
I saw in the example
you also used a service.
So my question, are
they still the same
or is there any difference
between 1 and 2?
MISKO: Yeah.
So the question
is about services.
The short answer is,
yes, it's the same,
but it's a little
more complicated
because in Angular2
we actually have
a hierarchical
dependency injector.
So in Angular 1
everything's a singleton.
In Angular2 things are
a singleton with respect
to their injector,
but because you
can have multiple
injectors you can
create injectors
and destroy them,
you can actually control
the lifetime of objects.
And this is done by
component in the annotation.
Not only does a
component declare
what template it wants
to use in a selector,
it can also
configurator an injector
for itself, for its shadow
root, and for its children.
And by configuring
and then bringing
the components on the page
through either [? ng ?]
or ng-repeat, or taking them
out by navigator or router,
you can actually
control the life time
of the services and
things that go with it.
So it's the same concepts
we're familiar with.
We made certain
vocabulary better
so you don't have to have
a confusion about what's
a service and what's
a factory and so on.
And we actually
gave it more power
so that you can have
this hierarchical things.
And you can lazy load
into your application
and unload modules and so on.
IGOR: I'll just try to
refactor what Misko said.
If you don't care about
having more power,
it's going to be the
same with better syntax.
If you want more features the
features will be available,
but you have to understand
how the hierarchical DI works.
But if you don't care,
don't worry about it.
BRAD GREEN: Thanks, Igor.
Another question.
Yeah?
Back there, then there.
(null)
AUDIENCE: So you talked a
lot about the templates,
but I remember at the time
there was a design doc about how
Angular supports data and the
synchronizing with the server,
maybe replacing the dollar HTTP
services, and stuff like that.
And now there's also David
here with the Firebase.
(null)
In Angular2 it will
be different for you
to write an AngularFire?
There will be different
stuff about that?
MISKO: So I'm going to
just mention something
and I'm going have both
of you guys answer it.
I think both Igor has something
to say because he's working
on the data services, and
obviously the Firebase--
David-- guy will have
something to say.
The first thing I
want to just say
is that because of
the Zones many things
will just magically work.
I cannot express to you just
how excited I am about Zones.
It is the bee's knees.
DAVID EAST: This is true.
MISKO: So David got
his Firebase thing
that was not meant
for Angular, just
a regular plain old Firebase.
And he pulled it in
into the Todo app,
and it just worked
out of the box
with not any kind of
apply, $scope.dollar apply,
or any of that stuff.
It's just all gone.
Having said that you can talk
more about the [INAUDIBLE].
(null)
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MISKO: He was asking
about [INAUDIBLE].
DAVID EAST: You
would answer that.
IGOR: So this is one
of the things that
is-- can you hear me?
OK.
So this is one of
the things that
is not as developed as
the templating part yet.
We're looking at different
solutions for the data layer,
including looking at observables
that are coming in ES7.
I think this is something
that could solve
many of the hard problems
that we're currently
having with the current
data approaches in Angular
or even outside of Angular.
And there are some other very
interesting things coming.
And we're going to talk
about that at ng-conf.
(null)
DAVID EAST: Is it on?
Oh, it's on.
Yeah. s far as the AngularFire
went, like Misko said,
the easiest part was the fact
that I started writing it
and it just worked.
There's was no-- when we write
it, the hardest part's keeping
everything synchronized,
but as far as [INAUDIBLE] as
far as Angular goes, is knowing
when to apply these things
and to do it in a
more efficient way.
And a lot of that Angular
internal knowledge
that we are constantly
refactoring and learning
more about, kind of
just disappeared.
And so when I wrote
it I was realizing
I wasn't writing any
Angular code at all.
It was all just JavaScript.
And all of that was because
of Zones, like you said.
So it was pretty magical.
BRAD GREEN: Cool.
Over here.
IGOR: I'll just add one
more thing to data layer.
The direction where
we're going, we
definitely don't want
to couple Angular
with a particular database
solution, or backend solution.
We want to be backend agnostic.
But we do want to provide some
of the options out of the box.
So that if you
want something, it
will be something supported
by the Angular team.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Hi.
Can you talk more about lazy
loading and loading on demand?
How it's going to be implemented
for complex applications?
MISKO: Lazy loading.
OK.
So you can have a
dependency injector
that is for your application.
And the router will navigate
to some sub-view, right?
And when you navigate
to the sub-view
the router can create
a new child injector.
And the child injector
requires a set of modules
to be configured with.
And those can be lazy loaded
from-- lazy loading script
code, that's not
difficult in itself.
What is difficult is to be
able to configure the injector.
And because of
the way components
are set up and
because even if you
noticed top level application
is just a component.
It's just components
all the way down.
There's really no
difference between saying,
oh, I'm loading a new child
component, which is lazily,
or I'm actually bootstrapping
a whole new child application.
The two are essentially
mentally equivalent.
And so the router is
going to be the key
to allow us to do lazy loading
of both the code and everything
else that comes with it.
(null)
AUDIENCE: They're going
to be configuration
where you say the logic
of lazy loading, right?
MISKO: Yeah.
So the router, when you
configure the router
you will specify what's the URL,
what's the component that you
get loaded for
that URL, and then
the component itself
will have instructions
on how to configure
the injector.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: Some
example to come.
OK.
Back here, and then up
there, and then back there.
OK.
Lots of questions.
AUDIENCE: Hey, I actually
have a simpler question.
I'm just curious
about your reasoning
for adding all of
those weird brackets
and all sort of
symbols in your DOM.
You're in the process
of simplifying it.
Might as well make it simpler.
MISKO: This is a simpler.
AUDIENCE: I mean,
I'm just curious
behind your reasoning
for all those weird--
IGOR: So the biggest
reason is removing
the ambiguity for
both humans and tools.
If you look at the
Angular 1 template,
it's very hard to reason about
which part of the template
is an Angular expression, which
part is a literal string, what
is a class name, or
any kind of value.
It's very hard to know this
except at run time when
the directive runs, or
Angular Compiler runs, that's
when we have the information.
And often the
information is only
available to the
directive itself.
The compiler often
doesn't even know
what's a value,
what's an expression.
So what we are trying to do is
make the syntax less ambiguous,
so that we can statically
analyze templates
without even knowing what
the directive is going to do.
This will enable us
to do two things.
People are going to be
able to easily reason
about the template.
They're going to understand,
OK, there is a binding here.
And the binding is
to this expression,
from this expression
to this property.
Or there's this Event
Handler, and it's
obvious from the syntax.
The other thing
is tools will also
be able to analyze templates
without understanding how
Angular and each directive
in Angular works.
So we'll be able to do things
like template transformations,
where we can minify
the template.
We'll be able to verify
the template and tell you,
hey, you made a typo
in this expression
because we know that the
component has only property
username and a user email,
and you typed, whatever,
gender or something else.
And we know that
gender doesn't exist,
or you made a typo in user
email and you misspelled it.
We're going to have that
information now available
to us.
So we can tell you, hey,
there's actually a typo.
Please go fix it.
And David already
mentioned that we're
trying to unify this
so that we don't need
to create new directives for
every event that is out there.
This is very important
for Web Components.
We need generic
syntax that just works
for Web Components,
or any custom events,
so that we don't need to
be extending the directive
library with every event
that people come up with.
MISKO: I want to actually
add something to it.
(null)
When you say, can we make it
simpler, and I kind of jokingly
said that we actually
did make it simpler,
the thing is when
you have something
that's different it
obviously kind of feels
like, well it's different.
You made it more complicated.
But let me give you
empirical data that shows you
that actually we made a simple.
You guys are familiar with
ng-click, ng-doublclick,
ng-mousemove, and
all the ng events
names, ng-show, ng-hide,
ng-storage, ng-disabled,
ng-enabled.
and probably I'm
missing somebody.
All those directives
I just named, gone.
They don't have to.
We don't need them
in the new syntax.
So we are actually
simplifying the whole thing.
Turns out, for example,
ng-show and ng-hide,
there's a property called
hidden on a DOM element.
And if you set it to
true, the DOM hides.
So all we have to do in
the new syntax is just say,
bracket, hidden, end
bracket equals true.
And this isn't some kind of
special directive like ng-show
that wakes up and does magical
things to the compiler.
We're just setting
up properties.
It's really as simple as that.
All of the events
systems are gone.
All the strings we had
to do with a image source
where we had to say, ng-source
because if you did source,
magical things would happen
and the browser would
try to pre-fetch
templates, double curlies.
For example ng-enabled
and ng-disabled
are there because enabled and
disabled property is special
and it has to be removed.
Binding the attribute
value to false,
will still make it disabled
because the disabled actually,
physically have to get removed.
So all these are examples
which simply disappear
in the new binding syntax
because when you say bracket
disable, you're actually
writing to the property, not
the attribute.
And so a lot of things
actually does get simplified.
So I just want to kind
of ask for your patience
and kind of realize that
just because it's different,
it doesn't make it
more complicated.
We really, really tried to go
back to the very basics of it.
And rethink why are we
doing all of these things.
And it will be different.
I totally understand that.
But there are good
fundamental reasons
why we did all these changes.
And they will be giving
you benefits long term.
AUDIENCE: Thanks.
BRAD GREEN: And believe it
or not, nobody mentioned it.
It's actually all
valid HTML, even
the bang side in front
of forEach somehow.
OK.
Another question here.
AUDIENCE: OK.
This one is a bit
specific, but what
happens if you have a
component, and let's say
you create another class
that inherits from that,
so extends that component.
And then use another
component annotation on that?
(null)
MISKO: The annotations
themselves do not inherit.
So if you subclass a component
and you don't give it
annotation it's as if
you don't know about it.
So you actually have to give
it a brand new annotation.
Actually if you start
playing with it,
it actually is the
proper behavior.
Now there's more
to it than that.
Just because you
annotate something,
it doesn't mean it's enabled.
So in Angular 1x once
you register directive,
that directive is
available everywhere.
And it makes code
reuse difficult
because if I register
a table directive
it's very likely, because
table is such a common word,
that somebody else will create
a different directive that
has the same name.
And they'll collide and
there will be problems.
With Angular 2x you import
the individual directives just
for your template.
And so different components
can have a different set
of directives that are imported.
And as a result, they
can have the same names
and it will not collide.
And which will further
aid reusability.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: Cool.
And was there one over here?
Yeah, there we go.
(null)
AUDIENCE: So in Angular
dot 1 dot whatever,
we had the config
and the run phases.
So what's happening with
the config and providers?
(null)
MISKO: So the config
phase is gone.
The dependency injection
system has a vocabulary
for-- it's kind of
closer to Guice,
if you're familiar with
that, where you say bind
something to either a
value or to a factory,
or we kind of specified
instructions on how
to make one of these things.
(null)
IGOR: Objects for configuration?
BRAD GREEN: You have
to mumble louder.
IGOR: So one of
the reasons why you
needed the provider
was to customize
how an object is instantiated.
And what we do now instead
of having this special phase,
we have config objects
that are injected
into the constructor
of each service
or each object that has
been instantiated by DI.
And using that config object
you can achieve the same thing
that you did with the
provider in the past.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: OK.
I know I have more
questions over here.
Back there?
Is there?
(null)
AUDIENCE: What is the
future of Angular 1.x?
I am mainly asking because
if we have a large project
and how soon we should
be targeting to upgrade,
or will there be a
possibility of a project
can partiality upgraded
to 2.0 and partially can
we use 1.3, or 1.4?
So that way we don't have
to migrate entire project,
but we can go phase by phase.
IGOR: Yeah.
Absolutely.
This is one of things we
are actually discussing.
How could we make it possible
to run Angular2 application
in an Angular2 application.
And in addition
to that, also how
could we run Angular2
application inside of Angular 1
application, or run
Angular 1 application
and Angular2 application
side by side in the same VM.
We don't have all
the answers yet.
It's something that is
totally on our mind.
And I think we'll
definitely need it
for any kind of large scale
migration of big applications.
So we're working on that.
Please don't upgrade to
Angular2 until it's ready.
It's not ready yet.
We are showing you this stuff
just to keep you in the loop
as to what's going on and get
your feedback because we still
can change things,
and sometimes we
just miss stuff or use cases.
And it's good to have
discussion about stuff that
is in progress.
So we are definitely
committed to 1x.
1.4 is launching around
the ng-conf timeframe.
We are already planning 1.5.
So 1x is nowhere to be dead,
even though the code base
is aging as David said.
That's just a fact.
(null)
The work we're
doing for Angular2
is because we know that
at one point in the future
Angular 1 is going
to be obsolete.
And we want to be
ready for that.
So we're committed
to supporting 1x.
We're going to talk
more about the migration
story and the support
story at ng-conf.
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
(null)
IGOR: Does the story include
[INAUDIBLE] from 1 to 2?
We'll talk about it at ng-conf.
We'll see.
As I said, Angular2's
not finished yet.
So we don't really know
what the options are.
Some kind of tooling that
would help the migration
is a possibility, but
we don't know yet.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Could you
talk a little bit more
about how you achieved
those performance numbers
that David was showing up there?
It was pretty impressive.
IGOR: We made them up.
[LAUGHTER]
MISKO: I wish it
was that simple.
AUDIENCE: No, I thought
Brad was the marketing
and you guys were in
engineering-- oh, never mind.
MISKO: So a lot of that is
actually, believe it or not,
documented.
So I'm trying to do a brain
dump of all this stuff.
And somewhere in
the Angular Repo
there is a folder called Docs.
And it talks about
how views work.
One of the things
we do in Angular2
is we're trying to
remove the need for you
to ever get a hold
of a DOM element.
So a link function is kind
of a common place where
you get a hold of
the DOM element,
and then you do all kinds of
magical things inside of there,
right?
So we removed that.
And because we removed
that we can really
reason about a
template statically.
So one of the things we can
do is we can reuse the views.
In the Angular 1x we can't
do it because once we
give the element
to a directive we
have no idea what you're
going to do with it.
You might destroy it.
You might remove it.
You might rearrange it.
And therefore we can
no longer reuse it.
As far as we're concerned
it's been mutilated
and it's no good for us.
Maybe a strong word.
So in Angular 2x,
because we don't actually
give you the element
we know exactly what
we have done to
the DOM structure.
And we know how to undo it.
And it turns out that this
is what allows a view caching
and that's a huge
performance improvement.
The other place is in Angular
1x you can kind of at any point
just say $scope.$watch and start
watching anything you want.
We made this all
declarative so then we
can pre-allocate all of the
data structures ahead of time
and figure out, OK, when
somebody instantiates
this particular
component, these are
all the watches that
they're going to have.
And what we do is we lay out
a prototypical component.
We lay out all of its
supporting data structures,
it's injectors, everything
you can possibly imagine.
We lay it all out.
And then when you say,
I need one of those,
it's super easy for us
to just make a copy.
Literally just go over
property by property,
and we just copy it over.
And it's very efficient.
And those are the two big kind
of tricks for us up our sleeves
that will give us this
performance boost.
But in order to
get that, we need
to be able to reason
about the template, kind
of a compiled template.
The compiler needs to know
where all the expressions are,
where are all the
variables, where
are all the sub templates.
And this is part of the reason
why the syntax have to change.
So that we could communicate
this to the compiler.
Also it turns out, it's
beneficial to the developer
because you can reason about it.
And it's the same
set of things that's
also beneficial to your tools.
Like your ID could
easily color code things,
can give you hints about
what is and isn't valid,
where you mistyped something.
So this is a kind of
an all around benefit
that you can get by
kind of rearranging when
in the lifetime
of an application
you're doing things.
BRAD GREEN: Questions over here?
IGOR: There is one more
organization that is actually
quite hard to notice until
you look under the hood.
In Angular 1 one of the
performance optimizations
is the compile phase.
If you're building directive you
have access to compile phase.
And when compile
phase is invoked
is when you're using a repeater.
Usually when you have a
element, or a component inside
of a repeater, we'll call the
compile function only once
for each repeater.
What Misko talked about, these
kind of static optimizations
that we are doing,
they happen once
per component in
the application.
So even if you have
two repeaters right now
side by side, they're
using the same component,
we call the compile phase,
or compile function once
for each repeater.
With all these optimizations
we can do just once
for application.
Even if you destroy the
view and recreate it,
we don't need to rerun it again.
So this is where a lot of
the performance comes also.
BRAD GREEN: Was there a
question over here somewhere?
There?
Yeah.
(null)
AUDIENCE: This is sort
of answered already,
but we're talking about
Angular 1 applications
that need to be
migrated at some point,
but if I'm planning to
start a new product today,
is there something
you would recommend?
And because we are
kind of lost between,
should we start with
Angular 1 and then
think about migrating
to Angular2,
because Angular2
is not yet ready.
Is there any
implementation techniques
you would recommend
that we can prepare also
to migrate to Angular2
when it's ready?
MISKO: When you're starting
a new project today,
Angular 1x is what you're
going to start with.
If you just want to
play with Angular2,
kind of see where it's heading,
whatever, for playing purposes,
by all means, you
can try the Todo app.
But understand that
everything's in flux still.
We could decide tomorrow that
bang forEach is a bad idea.
And it's going to
be something else.
And tough luck.
BRAD GREEN: By the
way, that would
be based on your input,
not just arbitrary whim.
That's why we're
doing these events.
MISKO: It would be based on
somebody basically coming to us
and telling us, oh, by the way,
this is the kind of problems
that it creates.
And then we would have to
go back to the drawing board
and say, OK, we didn't
think about that.
So let's rethink
this kind of a thing.
[INAUDIBLE]
IGOR: So when it comes
to particular techniques,
one thing that is probably going
to get you the furthest is just
think of your application
as components.
This was not as
important in Angular 1,
where we had controllers
and templates,
and the router would
combine them together.
In Angular2 everything
is a component.
And the router just
swaps around components,
instantiates components.
This is one of the things that
you can do today in Angular 1
to make the architecture
closer to Angular2.
The other thing you can start
doing is start using ES6.
There are many
transpilers out there.
We like Traceur, but you
can use whatever you want.
There's 6to5 and others.
I think you'll find ES6
very pleasant to use
and it will make
you more productive.
So why not start there?
Other suggestions?
I don't know.
We're going to talk more about
this stuff at the ng-conf.
We're going to make a
list of recommendations.
I haven't really
thought much about this.
MISKO: I would just say
stick to good old practices.
Don't write messy code.
That makes it easy to re-factor.
BRAD GREEN: Write your tests.
MISKO: Write your tests, yes.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: OK.
Back here.
(null)
AUDIENCE: When you
guys introduced track
by into ng-repeat I noticed that
it got a lot smarter obviously
about knowing when
to repaint what,
but ng-repeat is almost
always the bottleneck
in terms of performance
in the DOM, in my opinion.
Have you guys noticed
that by implementing Zones
that you've gotten
better performance,
it's a lot smarter about
knowing when to repaint things?
And can we expect to be
able to draw potentially
hundreds or thousands of things
on the screen using ng-repeat?
MISKO: So the
ng-repeat, the rendering
is not the bottleneck.
What it is is detecting
the changes, right?
IGOR: [INAUDIBLE].
(null)
MISKO: Well,
IGOR: In Angular 1 though.
MISKO: Depends how
you look at it, right?
Do you want to answer?
IGOR: Yeah, so I think your
question slightly unclear
because you are
assuming that Zones
is some kind of replacement
for track by in Angular 1.
Is that not the case or can
you clarify your question?
(null)
AUDIENCE: I assume,
yeah, by identifying
what has changed you guys are
able to accurately determine
what you need to
redraw using ng-repeat.
And via Zones you have
more fine tuned control
of determining what's changed.
So if you can identify
which element,
what single element has
changed then you could.
IGOR: So Zones actually
don't tell us what changed.
Zones only tell us
that something changed.
It's kind of a general
purpose trigger
to tell us about events that
are happening in the browser.
It's still up to us to
figure out what changed.
And this is where
new change detection
comes into play, where we can
scan a large amount of objects
and figure out what changed.
And David mentioned
some of the strategies
we are using, where we
can do kind of a tree
shaking, and just looking only
in certain parts of the graph
to determine what changed.
But I think if we are talking
about ng-repeat, specifically
in Angular 1x, I would bet that
the performance problems are
coming from the DOM render, from
creation of DOM, appending DOM
to the document.
And then having the
browser render it.
And those issues
are being addressed
by the view caching, and
all these smart things
we are doing with the compiler.
So we are addressing that.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: Question here, yeah?
AUDIENCE: There was
that one time discussion
of a long form versus
a short form syntax.
So instead of the square
brackets and curve braces,
or whatever that you would
also have a longer form.
So if people aren't
really into looking
at all of the syntax-y
looking things,
that there would
be an alternative.
Are you still thinking about?
MISKO: It's in there already.
(null)
BRAD GREEN: That part actually
has a doc somebody could read.
MISKO: I believe so, yeah.
That's actually described
in a templating doc.
Yes, go find the template dot
[? md, ?] something or other.
BRAD GREEN: Misko wrote it.
He forgot.
MISKO: It's horrible.
Is just a brain dump, so it's
not well-formatted or anything.
BRAD GREEN: More questions.
Back here.
OK.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Can you talk something
about Angular [INAUDIBLE] 2.x
being mobile for
us because that's
what a I heard couple
of months back.
And about testing
and finally when
can we get our hands onto
the final version of 2.x?
[LAUGHTER]
BRAD GREEN: I'll take that last
question, but go ahead, Misko.
MISKO: Mobile, there's a
couple things about mobile.
First of all, you want
to not drain the battery.
So you want to be the
most efficient possible,
both in terms of CPU usage
and memory usage, so you don't
force the app to stop out of
memory or something like that.
And the other part to the mobile
story is to have gestures.
So let's take each
one separately.
So for speed we have this,
what we call ultra fast change
detection, which I guess
wasn't covered in here, was it?
No.
OK.
So it turns out the way
the change detection does,
when we originally wrote
it, I kind of didn't
know much about how VMs work.
But it turns out we left
whole bunch of what's
known as polymorphic
calls inside of it.
BRAD GREEN: Megamorphic.
MISKO: Sorry.
Megamorphic.
Thank you.
And these megamorphic
calls are the worst thing
you can do to a VM.
And the VM really
does not like them.
So we re-factored, rebuild
the change detection.
We scratched our heads.
And we got this new
thing, which leaves
behind nothing but
monomorphic calls, sites.
And those are awesome
because the VM
knows how to inline them.
And so they make them
go really, really fast.
And fast on mobile means
don't kill the battery
while you're doing
change detection.
So that's step one.
Step two is we can actually,
if a component is well behaved,
and it makes certain
guarantees to us,
it's a little extra
work on your part,
but if you do those
guarantees to us,
then we can actually skip the
change detection altogether
for that particular component.
So we can kind of
do branch pruning,
the amount of stuff we
have to change detect just
gets shorter.
Saves the battery more.
And the next part is memory.
And so the change detection,
because of the way we do it,
we actually are also not
only efficient in CPU space,
but also in memory space.
And so the change
detection for 2.x
is a lot more efficient in
that department as well.
And finally, the event system,
when you do parentheses
and you put an event
name, it turns out
that that actually
doesn't go directly
to the element for the
add event listener.
Instead it goes to
a set of plug-ins
that can all vote
whether or not they
know how to intercept
a particular event.
And the last one in the
list is just going to DOM.
And the one in front
of that is something
that, for now, we're
just using Hammer.js.
And so you can say
parentheses, left swipe.
Or you can say parentheses,
pinch, or something like that.
And it just
understands, oh, I know
that DOM doesn't
know how to do it,
but I know because
there's Hammer.js,
it knows how to handle that.
And then properly set the event.
So those are the areas where
we make it nice for mobile.
IGOR: Lazy code loading?
There's more stuff.
Lazy code loading,
which is new for mobile.
We support that.
But also components.
And this is what Angular
material is about.
(null)
Within Angular 1 we kind
of started with this late
in the life cycle
of the framework,
but we want to provide a set
of components out of the box,
so that you can just use
those components to build
applications.
And these components
are mobile friendly.
They're mobile first.
The next thing is offline.
So with the data
layer that I mentioned
we are looking into offline
first as one of the-- like
making it smooth.
And just easy for
people to do that.
(null)
The new router is
mobile friendly.
And we're looking at
some other stuff that
would help navigation
on mobile, so.
BRAD GREEN: Wait.
He also asked about testing.
IGOR: Testing.
BRAD GREEN: I don't know why
that was glommed in there,
but we all love
testing so please.
IGOR: We love testing.
We're going to just
keep on doing testing.
We're adding more stuff.
At ng-conf they're going to talk
about accessibility testing.
David didn't mention,
but the graphs actually
come from-- the performance
numbers and graphs come
from a new tool that we
built for Angular that we
called Bench Press.
Then we are also going
to make something
that is available to you that
you can use for performance
testing in your application.
So not only are we
building it for Angular,
but also any
Angular application,
or even non-Angular
application-- because it's not
tied to Angular--
can use the same tool
for performance testing.
So we love testing.
We're going to do more testing.
We are exploring new
areas to do testing in.
AUDIENCE: So quick question.
Will there ever be
an Angular native?
Which compiles down to native?
IGOR: Maybe.
(null)
MISKO: Anything's possible.
BRAD GREEN: Do you want
to come do it with us?
So, Misko, talk a little
bit about the structure
and why this might be possible.
Really it's not in 1.x, but
it could be possible in 2.
MISKO: How deep should I go?
BRAD GREEN: You've
got three minutes.
MISKO: OK.
So one of the things
that I said earlier
is that in Angular2,
we work really
hard to make sure you
don't have to actually
ever get a hold of the DOM.
And so your whole application
can be written without DOM.
And because it can be
written without DOM,
you can run it
essentially anywhere.
Maybe a web worker.
Well, we're not sure
what that exactly means.
We're kind of toying
with this idea.
But if you have a web worker,
the other thing we have is
that all the DOM
updates happen through--
instead of dealing
with DOM, which
is kind of very low level,
we have this other thing
called the view.
And view is kind of the
structural, or logical way
of thinking about the app.
Views can be added or
removed, and so on.
And because it's view, it
creates a very nice interface
for serialization.
So if your application
runs on web worker,
it becomes really easy to
serialize all the deltas for it
across the wire, and
then send it over
to the UI thread, which then
can update all the operations.
But once you have that you
kind of squint and you go,
well, wait a minute.
Why does it have to be a
UI thread on a browser?
It could really be
just about anything
that gets these updates,
including maybe native.
That's as far as we got,
but if you have some ideas
we're kind of making sure we're
kind of designing this stuff
to keep the doors open.
BRAD GREEN: So no plans.
I know Facebook
has an announcement
of this native thing.
We would love to
partner with them.
We should go say hi to them.
That might be a thing.
OK.
Over here.
(null)
AUDIENCE: In
Angular 2.0, will it
be possible to append components
to other components at runtime?
MISKO: Yes.
AUDIENCE: Not from the start?
So getting a hold of other
components is one of the things
that you're going to
love in Angular 2.0.
The dependency injection system
in Angular 2.0 is amazing.
I don't know what else
I can say to you guys.
IGOR: [INAUDIBLE].
MISKO: No, he says,
how to get components
get a hold of other, no?
IGOR: [INAUDIBLE].
MISKO: Oh. append new
components at runtime.
(null)
I heard the question
I wanted to hear.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
(null)
MISKO: And so that would
be through lazy loading.
So that's how you can do it.
(null)
The other question was
a lot more interesting.
AUDIENCE: Will it be something
like you are using now?
$compile?
MISKO: All the dollar
signs are gone,
but yes, there is
a compile service.
It's something like that, yes.
I'm not sure.
It's not actually
clear to me how.
IGOR: It's like
creating dynamic views.
MISKO: I know.
But a lot of things are
kind of moved around
and you have to--
it gets complicated.
Yes, but the short answer
is there definitely
will be something like that.
And we need it for
lazy loading of views.
So this is going to happen.
The details are not kind
of figured out just yet,
but it's a requirement.
It's a hard requirement.
We're not going
to miss that one.
AUDIENCE: Just to know.
Thank you.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Do you have any plans
for sever side [? handering, ?]
especially because
of external crawling?
(null)
IGOR: Maybe.
So just like we
mentioned the native,
the architecture we have allows
us to do this kind of stuff.
One thing that we
already want to do
is do a template
precompilation, where
we will just-- just like
you minify your JavaScript,
we'll be able to
pre-compile templates.
And basically work
that is usually
done by the compiler
on the client side
during the startup
of the application
would be done during the
build step of the application.
And while we are at that we can
also extract all the metadata
we need to actually do service
side interpolation, which
would allow us to create a
system where you can pre-render
stuff on the server.
It's not something we are
actively working on right now,
but the architecture
we are building
takes this into account and
leaves it as a possibility.
AUDIENCE: Thanks.
(null)
AUDIENCE: Hello.
So one question that I have
also to the lazy loading
is more about, maybe
I remember wrong,
but someone during
ng-europe said
that the lazy loading will
be also available in 1.x.
Maybe I remember wrong?
The question is--
IGOR: I don't know.
I don't remember what exactly
was said at ng-europe.
Well, I remember many
things from ng-europe.
I don't remember
this particular one.
So I don't know how
it was formulated,
but what I can tell you is
that the lazy holding in 1x
is much more
complicated because we
don't have a hierarchical DI.
And the reason why, this
is kind of hard to explain,
but the reason why we don't
want to do lazy loading in 1x
is not because it's impossible.
It just would make the
application unstable.
And I think it would be very
easy to introduce bugs that'll
be very hard to debug,
and then the application
would just not work
in certain scenarios.
And this is what
we want to avoid.
We discussed how we could
and hierarchical injector
solves this problem.
So we don't have that
problem with Angular2
and we can just do lazy
loading without any issues.
In Angular 1x, however,
we are thinking
of some workarounds that
would allow us to provide you
this guarantees and
also do lazy loading.
The new router that we're
back-porting from 2.0 to 1x
makes it possible
to do lazy loading.
There is still some pieces that
need to be done in the core.
I don't think we'll have
enough time to do it in 1.4,
but it's on the table for 1.5.
AUDIENCE: Thanks.
Thank you.
BRAD GREEN: More questions?
(null)
Or if we're out, that's great.
That's a lot of questions.
OK.
Great.
Thank you, everybody.
It was wonderful to have you.
[APPLAUSE]
Come join us on one
of the live viewing
streams at ng-conf
unless you're coming
in person, which is awesome
too, where you'll hear more
about material design, the new
router, internationalization,
accessibility, more on testing,
all kinds of other good stuff.
We'll hope to see you there.
Thanks.
Bye.